CV / DEVOPS PETR OSPALÝ

petr@ospalax.cz · Brno, Czech Republic

My name is Petr Ospalý and I am working currently as a DevOps. I started my career in linux system administration (among other things) and built myself towards the software development - eight years of experience in the field. The emerging DevOps movement in the IT industry is bringing the system engineering and the software development together in a way I found intriguing and perspective.

CONTACT

Email: petr@ospalax.cz

Address: Brno, Czech Republic

Birth: 1988, Brno, Czech Republic

EXPERIENCE

SEP 2018 - PRESENT

DEVOPS/SW DEVELOPER, TIETO

Contributions to the ONAP (Open Networking Automation Platform) opensource project.

OCT 2016 - SEP 2018

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGINEER, SMART COMP

Linux system administration, DevOps, scripting, automation, docker containerization.

APR 2011 - SEP 2016

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR, EUROSAT CS/EUROSAT HOLDING

Linux and Windows system administration, virtualization, scripting, automation.

EDUCATION

NOT YET FINISHED - ON GOING (SINCE 2015)

BACHELOR DEGREE, UNIVERZITA PALACKÉHO V OLOMOUCI

Applied computer sciences - little challenging to study CS while working full time job.

2009

UPPER SECONDARY, GYMNÁZIUM (GRAMMER SCHOOL), BRNO, VÍDEŇSKÁ

A class specialized to a programming.

LANGUAGES

CZECH: NATIVE SPEAKER

ENGLISH: FLUENT

SKILLS

Unix, Linux, Czech, English, Shell, Bash, Sed, Awk, Scripting, C, Backup, PostgreSQL, Git, Gitlab, System administration, Automation, Virtualization, Kvm, Nginx, Docker, Docker-compose, Monitoring, Nagios, Saltstack, Python, Ansible, Kubernetes

LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

- O Debian/Ubuntu
- O RHEL/CentOS
- O Overall knowledge of the GNU/Linux OS and unix-like environments

SHELL SCRIPTING AND AUTOMATION

- O Bash, grep, sed, awk etc.
- O Shell scripts/utilities
- O Automation scripts (cron jobs etc.)
- O Ansible and saltstack

PROGRAMMING

- O C programming
- O Python
- O Custom python modules for ansible

VIRTUALIZATION, CLUSTERING AND HA

- O KVM, virsh, libvirt
- O Clusters (PostgreSQL, keepalived etc.)

MICROSERVICES AND ORCHESTRATION

- O Writing dockerfiles, docker-compose yamls, kubernetes manifests
- CI/CD
 - O Docker (swarm)
 - O Kubernetes
 - O GitLab (Travis CI)

DEPLOYING SERVICES AND PLATFORMS

- O Web servers (e.g.: nginx)
- O Databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL/MariaDB)
- O Information systems, CMSs, webapps etc.

ABOUT ME

I like the world of linux, the free options and the possibility to fix or create stuff by yourself for yourself. Writing scripts in both shell, python and other is fun and joy. I have urge to automate stuff and make the system self-sufficient – using HA, clustering and self-healing mechanisms. IT is a demanding and challenging field and it will require never ending learning and studying cycles – I love to learn new skills and gain new knowledge. Building or creating something (code or system) is rewarding and pleasant experience for me.